welcome to the first ever episode of
what's cooking in business
Central in the series The Business
Central developers themselves both
internal and external we'll present some
of the latest product additions shipping
with the upcoming major release yes
because during the business central two
major release events a lot of
information is being shared and it can
sometimes be difficult to spot some of
the smaller improvements that we've made
but with what's cooking our developers
get to Showcase their features right
after completion hopefully spot some
excitement what's about to come your
way every week we hope to offer you a
glimpse of what's cooking in business
Central celebrate the completion of
features with us take them for a spin
our public previews and let us know what
you think about our latest work are you
ready welcome to what
[Music]
cooking for this first demo let's look
into the edit sales price list in Excel
capability which will ship with
businessle 2025 Wave 1 for this demo we
need to make sure that the feature is
enabled so we go into feature
management we find our feature new sales
price experience and we see that it is
enabled now let's try out if the feature
works so we go to sales press list and
we addit our existing default sales
press list and for the sake of this demo
let's just say that if you sell more
than 10 ath desks the price will be
reduced from 1,000 to 800 verify that
the lines are okay done let's quickly
give this a try let's go into a sales
invoice and um there we go let's add our
Essence
desk uh and if we have8 eth desks the
price is 1,000 if we adjust that to 10
we see that it's now discounted to 800
so everything works as it's supposed to
nothing new so far but now if we go up
here you will see a new button edit in
Excel which wasn't there previously
let's click on
that so now it will create our Excel
spreadsheet how it syns our data from
business Central to
excel there we have our line and we can
find our unit price let's just say we
reduce it further we only want to charge
700 so now if we publish this this price
and we go
back and we will quickly refresh our
browser here we'll see that the price
was updated to 700 so this makes it
easier to edit prices now this was
highly requested on bcas 151 votes uh
and it was also mentioned that this
could be an open source contribution on
GitHub that it was open for that and
actually stepan Sage uh took the
opportunity and took on this task wrote
the code that is necessary to enable
this feature
and next thing you know this thing ships
with 2025 wave 1 thanks for watching